<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://mahdi-b.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://mahdi-b.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2024-07-30T00:11:56+00:00</updated><id>https://mahdi-b.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>A simple, whitespace theme for academics. Based on [*folio](https://github.com/bogoli/-folio) design. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Project Hokulani Students Develop AI EMR</title><link href="https://mahdi-b.github.io/blog/2024/project-hokulani-2/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Project Hokulani Students Develop AI EMR"/><published>2024-07-21T12:57:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-07-21T12:57:00+00:00</updated><id>https://mahdi-b.github.io/blog/2024/project-hokulani-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://mahdi-b.github.io/blog/2024/project-hokulani-2/"><![CDATA[<h3 id="high-school-interns-develop-chatgpt-powered-electronic-medical-record-system-prototype">High School Interns Develop ChatGPT-Powered Electronic Medical Record System Prototype</h3> <p><br/></p> <p>There’s a lot of excitement around AI these days, and for good reason – it’s transforming industries and reshaping the way we live and work. Every year, as part of the Hokulani Project, our lab hosts interns who learn about AI and take on exciting and innovative AI projects. This internship is not just about coding or algorithms; it’s about teaching the students to innovate, and push the boundaries of what’s possible with AI.</p> <p>Last year, interns built Resheipt (<a href="">https://www.hawaii.edu/news/2023/09/12/project-hokulani-resheipt-app/</a>). This summer, our latest cohort of interns developed an application called Parrot Forms, designed to assist doctors by automating the charting process.</p> <p>Here’s a quick overview: the application listens to post-appointment conversations between doctors and patients, transcribes them, and extracts key information such as chief complaints and symptoms. Using the Subjective-Objective Assessment Plan (SOAP) method, the app then enters this information into a mock electronic medical record application that the interns built from scratch, effectively acting as a digital assistant.</p> <p>Even without specialized software, these interns developed a tool that not only transcribes but also comprehends and organizes medical information, simplifying documentation for doctors. It’s more than just a scribe – it’s a comprehensive digital helper. The students, who hail from eight high schools in Hawaii, were able to build these tools by harnessing generative AI in various aspects, from learning and disambiguating medical concepts to problem-solving, design, and scripting a prototype.</p> <p>Our experience with the Hokulani Project and the incredible work our interns have done over the past three years is a testament to the real potential of AI. Beyond the entertainment aspect, AI is a powerful tool that, when harnessed correctly, can solve real-world problems and create innovative solutions. The projects our interns have completed not only highlight their talent and dedication but also underscore the profound impact AI can have when developed and guided thoughtfully.</p> <p>With tools like generative AI and sophisticated frameworks, the barrier to entry for developing robust applications has significantly lowered. This advancement promises fewer bugs, more secure systems, and cost-effective solutions. By creating Parrot Forms, our interns demonstrated that AI could effectively address critical needs in healthcare. As generative AI technologies continue to evolve and become more integrated into educational and professional settings, we believe the future of software development will be brighter, more reliable, and increasingly innovative.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="education"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[High School Interns Prototyope Integration of AI in EMR.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Unleashing the Power of AI</title><link href="https://mahdi-b.github.io/blog/2023/project-hokulani/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Unleashing the Power of AI"/><published>2023-08-31T12:57:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-31T12:57:00+00:00</updated><id>https://mahdi-b.github.io/blog/2023/project-hokulani</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://mahdi-b.github.io/blog/2023/project-hokulani/"><![CDATA[<h3 id="how-sail-interns-used-chatgpt-to-build-an-expense-tracking-app-in-just-two-weeks">How SAIL Interns Used ChatGPT to Build an Expense-Tracking App in Just Two Weeks</h3> <p><br/> The past summer has been quite a fun ride for our Lab. Akib Sadmanee and I, had the privilege of hosting seven exceptional high school students in a unique computer science internship under Project Hōkūlani. And what these students accomplished in a short two-week period is remarkable.</p> <p>Simplifying Complexity with AI When we started brainstorming ideas for the internship, one of the challenges was to pick a project that was ambitious but achievable. We decided to build a mobile app designed to help users track their expenses. Now, the exciting part of this isn’t just the app itself, but how we went about creating it.</p> <p>In the past, breaking down receipt information like vendor names, phone numbers, and item lists would require heavy lifting from machine learning experts. But our highschool students used ChatGPT to perform these tasks with what’s known as “prompt engineering.” This significantly sped up the development process, allowing us to focus more on education and less on coding.</p> <p>The students also utilized no-code platforms like Amazon Web Services to build various features such as user authentication and image uploading. And yes, ChatGPT was there to assist us with answering any technical questions that arose, making the process even smoother.</p> <p>What strikes me the most is how this experience highlights the influence of AI technologies like ChatGPT on the future of software development. If high school students can build such a complex app in just 40 hours, most of which was spent on learning rather than coding, imagine the technological advancements we can expect in the coming years.</p> <p>What’s next for next year interns? We’re not sure yet, but we’re excited to find out!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="education"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Students with no programming experience build app in two weeks.]]></summary></entry></feed>